peugeot.co.uk 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy | Peugeot UK

##  Peugeot Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement sets out all the information that we are required, by UK Data Protection laws, to provide to you about how Peugeot Motor Company plc (hereinafter referred to as “Peugeot”, “we” or “us”) will process your personal data.

This version of our Privacy Statement is effective from 30th May 2018.

  * 1\. Purposes and Legal Justification

  * 2\. Who do we share your personal data with?

  * 3\. Will your personal data be transferred?

  * 4\. How long do we keep your personal data for?

  * 5\. How do we use cookies?

  * 6\. What are your rights?

## Purposes and Legal Justification

**1.  What purposes does Peugeot process your personal data for and ** **what is the legal justification for this processing** **?**

**_The purposes for which we collect and process personal data are:_**

| 

**_We are lawfully permitted to use your personal data for this purpose because:_**  
  
---|---  
  
To fulfil your order, deliver or service your vehicle.

| 

It is necessary to enable us to perform our contractual commitments to you.  
  
To book any test drive or provide any brochure you request, provide a part exchange valuation or to respond to any query you might have.

| 

It is necessary in our legitimate interests to serve our customers properly.  
  
To provide, manage and respond to any requests you have made to us.

| 

It is necessary in our legitimate interests to ensure that we serve our customers properly.  
  
To help us identify you when you contact us.

| 

It is necessary in our legitimate interest to ensure that we serve our customers properly and provide you with a personalised service.  
  
To manage safety recalls and quality campaigns

| 

It is necessary to do this in order to comply with legal requirements.  
  
To provide you with the most user-friendly online navigation experience.

| 

It is necessary in our legitimate interest to improve our websites and provide you with the best possible experience when you visit our websites.  
  
For general administration, reporting, audit and analysis purposes and to manage our relationship with you

| 

It is necessary in our legitimate interests and to ensure the effective management of our business.  
  
For market research purposes, customer satisfiaction surveys and to carry our mystery shopping exercises. This helps us improve the quality of our products and services we provide.

| 

It is necessary in our legitimate interest to manage our business effectively and to improve our offering to you.  
  
To market to you and, where appropriate, to invite you to any events that we might organise.

| 

You have consented for us to contact you for these purposes. We will not contact you for these purposes unless you have consented.  
  
To help us detect and prevent fraud and money laundering and to recover any debts owed to us.

| 

It is necessary in our legitimate interests to protect our business.  
  
To comply with law for example if we are required by any law enforcement agency, court, regulator, government authority or other third party.

| 

It is necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
Pass on to any third party that purchases, or to which we transfer, all or substantially all of our assets or business. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to ensure that the entity to which we transfer your personal information uses it in a manner that is consistent with this Policy.

| 

This is necessary in our legitimate interests in order to manage our business.  
  
To carry out analysis and customer profiling. We may combine and analyse your personal information to help us develop and improve our products and services, understand our customers better; and to manage and improve our relationship with you. This could include, for example, informing our distribution strategy, evaluating the effectiveness of our marketing and customer service, conducting market analysis and identifying products or services which may be of interest to you.

| 

It is necessary in our legitimate interests to ensure that we personalise the service we provide to you and interact with you in the way that suits you best.  
  
## Who do we share your personal data with?

  **2.  ** **Who do we share your personal data with?**

The personal data we process will be shared by Peugeot on a need to know basis to a restricted number of third parties, depending on the purpose of the processing, as follows:

| 

Type of third party

| 

Reason for sharing  
  
---|---|---  
  
1

| 

Third parties who provide our Contact Centre services.

| 

To answer general queries and action brochure & test drive requests.  
  
2

| 

The Dealer Network of Peugeot UK

| 

To organise test drives, follow-up brochure requests, part exchange valuations and answer sales enquiries or queries about vehicle orders, servicing & maintenance.  
  
3

| 

 PSA Financial Services

| 

For any questions about your existing finance agreement.  
  
4

| 

Marketing & Advertising Agencies

| 

 To enable them to create our advertising campaigns, emails, newsletters, letters, brochures & social media posts.  
  
5

| 

Print & Fulfilment Partners

| 

To enable them to send material such as letters and brochures.  
  
6

| 

Data Management Partners

| 

To securely manage data.  
  
7

| 

Media Partners (such as Google, Amazon, Facebook and Sky).

| 

To advertise our products and services.  
  
8

| 

Technology Partners and IT service providers

| 

To manage services on our websites, for example Part Exchange Valuation And to help us maintain our IT systems.  
  
9

| 

Analysis Partners

| 

Analyse how our websites are navigated how effective our advertising campaigns are and which products and services are of most interest.  
  
10

| 

Market Research Partners

| 

To research how you use your vehicle, what you like and what you dislike and what we need to do in order to increase your satisfaction and improve our products and services going forward.  
  
11

| 

Credit Card Payment Processors

| 

To securely process credit card payments.  
  
12

| 

Driver & Vehicle Licencing Agency (DVLA)

| 

Organisation that keeps a register of licenced vehicles in the UK.  
  
## Will your personal data be transferred outside the EU?

**3\. Will your personal data be transferred outside the EU?**

We may transfer your Information to a country outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"), provided that the country to which the personal data are transferred ensures an adequate level of protection for your rights and freedoms. If this country does not offer the same level of data protection as the European and local data protection legislation, Peugeot will take adequate measures to ensure that the collected personal data is processed in accordance with the applicable legislation relating to data protection.

Personal data we hold may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. That staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of contracts with you, the processing of payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting Information to us, you agree to this transfer, storage and processing.

## How long do we keep your personal data for?

**4\. How long do we keep your personal data for?**

The length of time we will keep your personal data for will depend on the purpose we are processing it for. However, in deciding how long we need to keep it for, we will apply the following criteria:

-  We will keep personal data for the minimum period we need to for the purpose(s) we collected it for  as described in Article 1 above.;

\- Your personal data are then archived as required by law for the length of time we are legally required to keep it for

\- Your personal data are then anonymized or deleted.

For more information, you can also contact our Data Protection Co-ordinator by email to  **[dataprotectionuk@mpsa.com](mailto:dataprotectionuk@mpsa.com?subject=Peugeot.co.uk%20|%20Data%20Protection%20Query)**  or by post to the Head of Compliance, c/o Peugeot Customer Care, Peugeot Citroën Automobiles UK Ltd, Pinley House, 2 Sunbeam Way, Coventry, CV3 1ND.

## How do we use cookies?

**5.   How do we use cookies on our websites, apps and other digital media?**

'Cookies' are small pieces of information sent to your device and stored on its hard drive to allow our websites to recognise you when you visit.

When you visit our website or use our applications or other digital media, We may, subject to your consent, use cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies to collect the following data:

  * IP address, login information, browser type, location, time zone, operating system, and other technical information
  * Information about your visit, including the websites you visit before and after our website and products you viewed
  * Length of visits to pages on our website, and page interaction information

Please see our  **[Cookies Policy](http://www.peugeot.co.uk/cookies-policy/)**  for further information **.**

## What are your rights and how can you exercise them?

**6\. What are your rights and how can you exercise them?**

Data Protection laws give you a number of rights in relation to the personal data we hold about you. In particular, you have the right to access your personal data, to have it corrected (where it is inaccurate or incomplete) and, in certain circumstances to have it erased, restricted or transferred to a third party. You also have the right to object to it being processed. You should be aware that not all of these rights apply in every instance therefore, in some cases, we would not have to comply. If you are unhappy about how Peugeot has handled (or is handling) your personal data, you have the right to complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office (“ICO”). You can do this by visiting www.ico.gov.uk. The ICO can investigate your claim and take action against anyone who’s misused personal data.

You can also withdraw your consent at any moment if the processing is based on your consent. To unsubscribe from emails from Peugeot or to manage your contact preferences please **[click here](https://preferences.peugeot.co.uk/email)**.

You can exercise these rights on simple request to our Data Protection Co-ordinator by email to  **[dataprotectionuk@mpsa.com](mailto:dataprotectionuk@mpsa.com?subject=Peugeot.co.uk%20|%20Data%20Protection%20Query)**  or by post to the Head of Compliance, c/o Peugeot Customer Care, Peugeot Citroën Automobiles UK Ltd, Pinley House, 2 Sunbeam Way, Coventry, CV3 1ND.
